Finding Aid for the Norman Stuart Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Norman Stuart Collection
1930–1980
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0423
.42 linear_feet
Biography/History
Norman Stuart was an actor and dialogue director. He played with Alfred Lunt and Lynn Fontanne in The Taming of the Shrew. With Ina Claire in Biography, with Judith Anderson in Family Portrait, in Street Scene.
Scope and Contents
This .21 linear feet collection contains 35 pieces of correspondence, nine photographs, and one theatrical program. Subjects in the correspondence cover the theatre, television, World War II, V-E Day, general notes, telegrams, and thank you notes. Please note that some correspondence has been glued on sheets with other correspondence.
- Correspondence – Incoming – (35)
  - Cornell, Katharine, February 28; telegram
  - February 28, thank you note
  - March 31, 1942, letter
  - n.d, telegram
  - Ferber, Edna, October 28, 1941; telegram
  - October 29, 1941, note
  - Fontanne, Lynn, July 1, 1941; letter
  - December 27, 1943, letter
  - December 26, 1950, christmas note
  - May 24, 1971, letter
  - November 8, 1971, letter
  - March 1, 1972, letter
  - April 6, 1972, letter
  - April 17, 1972, letter
  - December 26, 1978, thank you note
  - March 14, 1979, thank you note
  - n.d, letters
  - n.d, sympathy card
  - n.d, christmas greeting
  - Hayes, Helen, July 16, 1940; letter
  - Lansbury, Angela, July 1, 1968; letter
  - Lunt, Alfred, June 17, 1941; thank you note
  - June 24, 1944, letter
  - November 4, 1976, letter
  - February 11, 1977, thank you letter
  - Robson, Flora, August 1; letter
  - September 8, 1944, letter
  - November 15, 1944, christmas letter
  - September 15, 1945, letter
  - Webster, Margaret, March 25, 1942/43; letter
  - May 14, 1945, letter
  - Whitty, May, August 18, 1939; letter
- Photographs – (9)
  - Judith Anderson in “Family Portrait”, 1939
    - Norman Stuart seated at rear end of table
  - Ina Claire in “Biography”, 1932
    - Inscription and autograph on front
  - Katharine Cornell in “Candida”, 1937
  - Francine Larrimore
  - Lunts, “Taming of the Shrew” tour
    - Played Nashville later 1939 or early 1940
    - Inscription and autograph on front
  - Selene Royle
    - Inscription and autographed on front
  - Norman Stuart playing “Sam” in “Street Scene”, 1930
    - Mary Wall played “Rose”
  - Norman Stuart – 50 years later –, 1980
    - TV Film “Legend of Lizzie Borden”
  - Margaret Webster, directed and played in “Family Portrait”, 1939
    - Inscription and autograph on front
- Program – (1)
  - “Biography” with Ina Claire, 1932